A Guide to the Richmond, Fredericksburg, and Potomac Railroad Records, 1834-1997
Library of Virginia
- Series II: Legal Department 1834-1986, 12.8 cubic feet and 26 volumes. (Box 28-63)
  - II.C. Contracts 1867-1969
    - II.C.3. Credit Bonds & Bonds Covering "Order Notify" Shipments n.d., 1916-1942
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds D-E (Box-folder 49:5)
        Includes: D.W. Windelman Co., 96 hour credit, 6 Mar 1942; Dunlop Mills, Surety Bond, 10 Aug 1918; Bond, 15 May 1936; E.M. Todd Co., Bond, 19 Jun 1925
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds F (Box-folder 49:6)
        Includes: First National Bank of Boston, Traveler's Checks, 2 Aug 1926; Ford Motor Co., Bond, 8 Mar 1924; Bond, 9 Dec 1924; Bond, 12 Jul 1925; Correspondence, 1933
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds G (Box-folder 49:7)
        Includes: G.R. Coleman, Indemnifying Bond dated 27 Oct 1924 not included; correspondence only; George P. Lyon Excelsior Co., Bond, 17 Jul 1924; Georgia Wholesale, Bond, Jul 1929; Green Wish Co., Bond, 13 Aug 1924
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds H-Ja (Box-folder 49:8)
        Includes: H.D. Lipford Grovery Co., Bond, 2 Nov 1926; International Harvester Co., Letter, 11 Apr 1929; J.R. Sherwood, Credit Application, 25 Jun 1921; James G. Gill Co., Bond, 22 Mar 1927
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds Jo-Mi (Box-folder 49:9)
        Includes: John F. Kincaid, Bond, 2 Jul 1934; Jones Motor Car Co., Bond, 3 Jun 1927; Jones Motor Car Co., Bond cancellation, 6 May 1929; Koiner Flour Mills, Correspondence, 1925; Larus & Brother Co., Bond, ca. 1926 Milwaukee Drug & Distributing Co., 26 Jun 1935
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds M (Box-folder 50:1)
        Includes: Mutual Ice Co., Bond, 7 May 1921, 5 May 1926
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds N-O (Box-folder 50:2)
        Includes: National Pepsi-Cola Corp., Bond, 13 Aug 1929, 3 Nov 1930, n.d.; Northern Neck Motor Co., Bond, 16 Mar 1929; Oakland Motor Car Co., Bond 3 Jun 1929
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds - Pa (Box-folder 50:3)
        Includes: Patrick-Young Co., Bond, 21 Feb 1921; Patrick-Young Co., and/or E.M. Todd Co., Bond, 7 Jan 1932
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds Pe-Pr (Box-folder 50:4)
        Includes: Peatross Manufacturing Co., Bonds, 6 Jan 1931; Polk-Miller Products Corp., Bond, 2 Nov 1928; Producers Co-operative Exchange, Bond, 10 Jul 1930
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds - R (Box-folder 50:5)
        Includes: Republic National Bank of Dallas, Texas, Travelers' Checks, Dec 1939; Richard Fulton Thompson, Bond, 23 Jun 1927; Richmond Dry Goods Co., Bond, 29 Aug 1940; Richmond Union Stock Yards, Bond, 18 May 1929; 15 may 1930
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds - S (Box-folder 50:6)
        Includes: Sam E. Finley, 96 hour credit, 9 Sep 1936; Sanitary Grocery Co., Lost bill of lading, 5 Oct 192?; Spotless Co., Bond 1 Aug 1918; Strauss Co., Letter, 10 Jun 1931
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds - T (Box-folder 50:7)
        Includes: T.B. Pearman & Co., Bond, n.d.; Taylor & Sledd, Bonds, 10 Jun 1927; Tobacco By-Products & Chemical Corp., Bond cancellation Aug 1939
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds - V (Box-folder 50:8)
        Includes: Virginia Baking Co., Bonds, 9 Nov 1925; Virginia Sales & Services Corp. Letter, 11 Mar 1931; Virginia Shipbuilding Co. and Washington Southern Ry. Co., 24 Feb 1919
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds - Wa (Box-folder 50:9)
        Includes: W.C. Quarles Co., Bond, n.d.; Warner Moore & Co. Bond, 28 Dec 1918; cancelled Bond 29 May 1932; Washington Brick Co., 96 hour Credit, 29 Jul 1939
      - Credit Bonds & Bonds We-Wy (Box-folder 50:10)
        Includes: West Brothers Brick Co., 96 hour credit, 15 Jun 1939; Weyerhauser Timber Co., 96 hour credit, 23 Jan 1941; White Construction Co., Letter re: Bonds, 30 Apr 1926; White Construction Co., Bond, 3 May 1926; Wortendyke Mfg. Co., Bond, 27 Oct 1924; Wyatt-Prock Lumber Co., Bond, 1 Dec 1924
  - II.D. Real Estate n.d., 1929-1986
    Files also include real estate records for subsidiaries Richmond Holding Corp. and Richmond Land Corp.; includes copies and drafts of agreements, deeds, correspondence, plats and plans, releases, etc.; organized according to internal numbering system; for financial aspects of real estate owned, see under Finance Series III.B.10 Property
    - Property Book n.d., 1 vol. (Box 50A)
      hand drawn and colored plans of property, with excerpts from Deeds; Deeds abstracted date ca. 1865-1907; kept in original leather case
    - Real Estate Files
      - 7:1:27 - R.F. & P. R.R. - City of Richmond, 3,884 s.f. (alley between Broad, Harrison); City Ordinance 74-19-26 1973-1974 (Box-folder 51:1-3)
      - 7:1:28 - Richmond Metropolitan Authority, 1,624 s.f. (7th St.) 1969-1974 (Box-folder 51:4-6)
      - 7:2:18 - Richmond Holding Corp. - Tucson Homes Corp. - Sale to, 1958 (Box-folder 51:7-11)
      - 7:2:19 - Richmond Holding Corp. - Acca Temple - Sale to, 1958, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 51:12-13)
      - 7:2:20 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Richmond Terminal Railway Co., Sale to, 1959, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 51:14)
      - 7:2:21 - Richmond Holding Corp. - Labek Corp., Sale to, 1959 (Box-folder 51:15-17)
      - 7:2:22 - Richmond Holding Corp. - Trustees Christ Episcopal Church, Sale to, 1960 (Box-folder 52:1-3)
      - 7:2:23 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Wythe-Hudson Corp., Purchase from, 1960, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 52:4)
      - 7:2:24 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Progressive Realty Corp., Sale to, 1962, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 52:5-6)
      - 7:2:25 - Richmond Holding Corp. - Mary A. Griffith, Sale to, 1959, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 52:7)
      - 7:2:27 - R.F. & P. R.R. - City of Richmond, Exchange (Westwood Ave., and new bridge over Acca Yard) 25 Aug 1976, 1 letter only (Box-folder 52:8)
      - 7:2:29 - R.F. & P. R.R. Co. - Va. Dept. of Highways, Dedication for use of 675 sq. ft. of Westwood Ave. 1966, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 52:9)
      - 7:2:30 - R.F. & P. R.R. and Richmond Land Corp. - Va. Dept of Highways, exchange 1971-1973 (Box-folder 52:10-13)
      - 7:2:33 - R.F. & P. R.R. Co. - Hoard P. Foley, Sale to (Lanvale Ave.), 1969-1975 (Box-folder 53:1-4)
      - 7:2A:01 - Richmond Land Corp. - Will, Matt P., Purchase from at Acca, 1939, 1952, 1955 (Box-folder 53:5)
      - 7:2A:05 - Richmond Land Corp. - Universal Tractor Co., Sale to (Deep Run Hunt Club Parcel), 1947-1962 (Box-folder 53:6)
      - 7:2A:06 - Richmond Land Corp. - Dedication of Westmoreland St. Ext 1951 (Box-folder 53:7)
      - 7:2A:07 - Richmond Land Corp. - Moninger, Bessie D., Sale to (Ext. of Westmoreland St.), 1952, 1956 (Box-folder 53:8)
      - 7:2A:08 - R.F. & P. R. R., Richmond Land Corp. - Virginia Conference Orphanage, Purchase from, 1949-1958, 1969 (Box-folder 53:9-12)
      - 7:2A:09 - Richmond Land Corp. - Wilton, S.M., Sale to (Westmoreland St.), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 54:1)
      - 7:2A:11 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Richmond Land Corp., Purchase from, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 54:2)
      - 7:2A:12 - Richmond Land Corp. - E. Carlton Wilton, Inc., Sale to (Westmoreland St.), 1954-1963 (Box-folder 54:3-4)
      - 7:2A:13 - R.F. & P. R.R., Richmond Land Corp. - Southern Materials Co., Inc., Sale to (E. line Loumour St. Ext. to Acca), 1955-1969 (Box-folder 54:5-8)
      - 7:2A:14 - R.F. & P. R.R., Richmond Land Corp. - Wilton, E. Carlton, Sale to (s/w corner of proposed Mavern Ave.) - Lessee Spotless C. Inc. (Shipper-Side Track Contract), 1954-1958, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 54:9-10)
      - 7:2A:15 - Virginia Electric & Power Co., Sale to (Acca), 1954-1955 (Box-folder 54:11)
      - 7:2A:16 - Richmond Land Corp. - Thalhimer Bros., Exchange with, 1952-1955 (Box-folder 54:12-14)
      - 7:2A:17 Richmond Land corp. - Shade & Wise, Inc., Sale to (Tomlynn St.), 1955-1971 (Box-folder 55:1-2)
      - 7:2A:18 - R.F. & P. R.R., Richmond Land Corp. - Provident Life & Accident Insurance Co., Sale to (Sears Warehouse), 1955-1957 (Box-folder 55:3-6)
      - 7:2A:19 - Richmond Land Corp. - GTM Properties, Inc. (Owner); Home Shop, E.A. (Shipper) (2001 Dabney Rd.), 1956-1984 (Box-folder 55:7-9)
      - 7:2A:21 - R.F. & P. R.R., Richmond Land Corp. - E. Carlton Wilton, Inc., Sale to (corner Dabney Rd. and Jacque St.), 1954-1964 (Box-folder 56:1-4)
      - 7:2A:22 - Richmond Land Corp. - F.M. Properties, Sale to (Corner Westwood Ave. & Dabney Rd.; Massey Builders' Supply Corp.), 1957-1984 (Box-folder 56:5-8)
      - 7:2A:23 - Richmond Land Corp. - Duchess Realty Corp., Sale to (100' on Dabney Rd.), 1958-1963 (Box-folder 56:9-10)
      - 7:2A:24 - Richmond Land Corp. - Graybar Electric Co., Inc., Sale to (Tomlynn Street), 1957-1962 (Box-folder 57:1-3)
      - 7:2A:25 - R.F. & P. R.R. - City of Richmond, Easement (Jacque St.), 1958-1959 (Box-folder 57:4-6)
      - 7:2A:26 - Richmond Land Corp. - Virginia Paper Company, Inc., 1960-1966 (Box-folder 57:7-10)
      - 7:2A:27 - Richmond Land Corp. - R.F. & P. R.R., Easement (Property between Westwood & Jacque & property line in common), 1964 (Box-folder 57:11)
      - 7:2A:28 - Richmond Land Corp. - R.F. & P. R.R., exchange (.34 Acre, Dabney Rd.), 1963-1964 (Box-folder 57:12-13)
      - 7:2A:30 - Richmond Land Corp. - Henrico County, Dedication to (550' Tomlynn St. Extension), 1964-1966 (Box-folder 58:1-2)
      - 7:2A:31 - Richmond Land Corp. - Henrico County, Deed/Exchange; Maywill & Thalbro Streets for Area Dabney Rd. & Deane Rd. r/w 1967-1969 (Box-folder 58:3-4)
      - 7:2A:33 - Richmond Land Corp. - Henrico Co., dedication to (Plat Westwood Ave., Tomlynn; Jacque and Portion of Dabney Rd.), 1955, 1970 (Box-folder 58:5)
      - 7:2A;34 - Richmond Land Corp. - Sears-Mims Exchange (Fairfax Co.), 1970-1972 (Box-folder 58:6-14)
      - 7:2A:35 - Richmond Land Corp. - Harvey H. Morris, Sale to (1.015 ac., Tomlynn St.), 1972-1976 (Box-folder 59:1-6)
      - 7:3:01 - R.F. & P. R.R. - F.W. Dabney, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1929 (Box-folder 59:7)
      - 7:3:02 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Home Beneficial Life Insurance Co., Purchase from, 1943 (Box-folder 59:8)
      - 7:3:03 - R.F. & P. R.R. - C.H. Phillips, Purchase from, 1942 (Box-folder 59:9)
      - 7:3:04 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Chelf Estate, Purchase from, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 59:10)
      - 7:3:05 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Lorean C. Niedermayer, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1943 (Box-folder 59:11)
      - 7:3:06 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Dabney Estate, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1943 (Box-folder 59:12)
      - 7:3:07 - R.F. & P. R.R. - W.R. Young, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1943 (Box-folder 59:13)
      - 7:3:08 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Paul Christoph, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1943 (Box-folder 59:14)
      - 7:3:09 - R.F. & P. R.R. - W.B. Proctor, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1943 (Box-folder 59:15)
      - 7:3:10 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Susie A. Warburton, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1941-1943 (Box-folder 59:16)
      - 7:3:11 - R.F. & P. R.R. - R.W. Walsh, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1943 (Box-folder 59:17)
      - 7:3:12 - R. F. & P. R.R. - W. Hugh Sanders, Purchase from (at Dumbarton), 1943 (Box-folder 59:18)
      - 7:3:13 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Richmond, City of, exchange (at Bryan Park), 1943-1945 (Box-folder 59:19)
      - 7:3:15 - R.F. & P. R.R. - T.A. Cary Estate (near Bryan Park), 1951-1954 (Box-folder 59:20-21)
      - 7:3:17 - Richmond Land Corp. - Harriett B. West, Purchase from, (Land near Morrison - MP3) 1956-1957 (Box-folder 60:1)
      - 7:3:18 - Richmond Holding Corp. - Virginia ABC Board, Sale to (Laburnum Ave.), 1958-1969 (Box-folder 60:2-7)
      - 7:3:19 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Georgia Pacific Corp. 1963-1974, 6 of 14 folders; continued in box 61 (Box-folder 60:8-13)
      - 7:3:19 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Georgia Pacific Corp. 1963-1974, 8 of 14 folders; continued from box 60 (Box-folder 61:1-8)
      - 7:3:20 - R.F. & P. R.R. and Richmond Land Corp. - County of Henrico, Dabney Road (Jacque St. to Bethlehem Road) 1963-1966 (Box-folder 61:9-10)
      - 7:3:21 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Virginia ABC Board, Deed/Exchange and Repurchase 1963-1969 (Box-folder 61:11-15)
      - 7:3:22 - R.F. & P. R.R. - Virginia Dept. of Highways, Interstate Route 64 1962-1966 (Box-folder 62:1-5)
      - 7:3:23 - Richmond Holding Corp. - Virginia Dept. of Highways, Interstate Route 64 1964-1966 (Box-folder 62:6-9)
      - 7:3:24 - Richmond Land Corp. - Virginia Dept. of Highways, Interstate Route 64 1964-1966 (Box-folder 62:10-12)
      - Crystal Park Residential Buildings, Agreements (Smith Group and Park Rental Associates) 21 Nov. 1986 (Box-folder 62:13-14)
  - II.E. Miscellaneous Files 1869-1942
    - Legal Opinion 1869-1871 (Box-folder 63:1)
      Includes: Johnston & Williams, 22 Feb 1869; Conway Robinson, 12 Aug 1869; Andrew Johnston, 26 Nov 1870; Johnston & Williams, 7 Feb 1871
    - Legal Opinion 1872-1876 (Box-folder 63:2)
      Includes: Conway Robinson, 13 Jul 1872 and 28 Mar 1874; P.V. Daniel, Jr., 2 Feb 1876 and 21 Dec 1876
    - Legal Opinion 1879 (Box-folder 63:3)
      Includes: P.V. Daniel, Jr., 24 Apr 1879
    - Legal Opinion 1880 (Box-folder 63:4)
      Includes: P.V. Daniel, Jr., 25 Mar 1880, 21 May 1880, 27 May 1880, "supplemental"
    - Legal Opinion 1881-1886 (Box-folder 63:5)
      Includes: George W. Biddle, 29 Mar 1881; Conway Robinson, 6 Dec 1881; A.M. Callum, 10 Jun 1886
    - Legal Opinion 1888, 1899, n.d. (Box-folder 63:6)
      Includes: George W. Biddle, 17 Dec 1888; Hill Carter, 1 Jun 1899; R.T. Daniel, Esq., n.d.
    - Regulations Jul 1914 (Box-folder 63:7)
      Includes: Interstate Commerce Commission: Classification of Operating Expenses (...), Income, Profit and Loss (...), prescribed by the Interstate Commerce Commission; as well as Regulations to Govern the Destruction of Records of Steam Roads
    - Releases 1935, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 63:8)
      Includes: Catherine A. Smith, 22 May 1935; Bernard H. Graninger, 13 Dec 1941; John S. Graninger, Dec 1941; Eleanor Patterson, 17 Sep 1942
- Series III: Finance Department, 1834-1995, 68.2 cubic feet and 371 volumes. (Box 64-255)
  Financial Files are organized into 4 subseries: Treasurer's Files; Accounting and Bookkeeping; Securities; and Taxes. The financial records make up the bulk of this collection. Treasurer's files include information on R.F. & P. securities owned, the company's 1941 re-funding, as well as financial aspects of the company's transition to CSX, and financial statements prepared for the Board.
  The Accounting and Bookkeeping section is divided into 11 categories: Accounts, n.d., ca. 1834-1978 contains information on expenses for various projects; Annual Reports, 1836-1995, consists of reports to the stockholders, with the exception of one report from 1839 addressed to the Board of Public Works (which held two fifth of the stock at that time) and one report for Richmond and Petersburg R.R. Co. for the year 1861 - there are volumes for individual years, multiple years, volumes that are bound with proceedings, statement, mortgages, etc., as well as reports for R.F. & P. and the Washington Southern R.Y. combined, for the years the two companies were managed together, 1901-1920; Auditor's reports are included for the years 1908-1965; Balances, 1834-1916, include Balance Sheets and Financial Analysis, as well as General Balance Sheets and Financial Analysis and one Trial Balance volume. Check Registers, 1907-1941; Day Books, 1860-1905; Income and Expenses, 1926-1972; Journals, 1834-1960; Ledgers, 1905-1960; and Vouchers, document the ongoing financial dealings and activities of the R.F. & P. Journals record costs of road repair depot and train expenses, bills payable, petty accounts, and interest on bonds, certificates of debt, and dividends paid; ledgers record assets, investments, debits, liabilities, surplus, credits, profit & loss, income, etc. The section on Properties, ca. 1973-1992, throws light on the type of properties owned and the many financial aspects involved including valuation, betterment and depreciation, by recording and analyzing specific types of financial and technical data. An exception is the Inventory of Property, 1873, which includes plans and drawings, in addition to listings of various other properties.
  The subseries Securities, 1834-1957, contains a large number of certificates, registers, and transfer books, for Bonds, 1866-1939; Certificates of Debt, 1844-1901; Dividends, 1861-1957; and Stocks, 1834-1975. They provide a good insight into financial status and ownership of the company at different points in its history.
  Tax records cover the period 1914-1992. Until an agreement with the Commonwealth of Virginia in 1912, the R.F. & P. had a tax exempt status. Federal Tax Returns include for the most part copies of returns, instructions, schedules, income statements, worksheets, receipts, correspondence, balance sheets, etc. For some years, records of wholly-owned subsidiaries, like Richmond Land Corp. and Washington Southern R.Y. Co. are included as well. State Tax Returns and Rolling Stock Information include copies of returns, schedules, and in some cases statement of property value and taxes extended made by the State Corporation Commission of Virginia. Included are also two filing units, 1980-1992, that deal with Real Estate and Property tax questions, and miscellaneous tax subject files, 1914-1973.
  - III.A. Treasurer's Files, 1922-1992
    Includes information on R.F. & P. securities owned, the 1941 re-funding, as well as financial aspects of the company's transition to CSX, and financial statements prepared for the Board.
    Arranged chronologically; the files within each section are kept in original order.
    - III.A.1. Securities owned, 1922-1935
      - Treasurer's Record of Securities Owned., 1 vol. (Box 64)
    - III.A.2. 1941 Re-Funding
      Internal filing number 355; kept in original filing order.
      - 1941 Re-Funding: Correspondence, 6 Jan-6 Feb 1941 (Box-folder 64:1)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: Correspondence, 11 Feb-7 Mar 1941 (Box-folder 64:2)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: Correspondence, 11 Mar-14 Mar 1941 (Box-folder 64:3)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: Correspondence, 21 Mar-18 Aug 1941 (Box-folder 64:4)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: General Mortgage (Proof), 8 Feb 1941 (Box-folder 64:5)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: General Mortgage (Proof and changes) (Box-folder 64:6)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: General Mortgage (Box-folder 64:7)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: Insurance Companies, Jan 1941 (Box-folder 64:8)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: Insurance Companies, 13 Feb-21 Mar 1941 (Box-folder 64:9)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: Application to Interstate Commerce Commission (Box-folder 64:10)
      - 1941 Re-Funding: application to Interstate Commerce Commission, Finance Docket 13173, 2 copies (Box-folder 64:11-12)
    - III.A.3. Transition CSX, 1989-1982
      Internal numbering system indicated by [ ].
      - Transition CSX: Transition index for files [1] - [25] (Box-folder 65:1)
      - Transition CSX: [1] Problems, 1991 (Box-folder 65:2)
      - Transition CSX: [2] forms, 1991 (Box-folder 65:3)
      - Transition CSX: [3] Bank accounts, 1991 (Box-folder 65:4)
      - Transition CSX:[4] FELA, 1991 (Box-folder 65:5)
      - Transition CSX: [5] Recording Tax, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 65:6)
      - Transition CSX: [6] Notes and Minutes, 1991 (Box-folder 65:7)
      - Transition CSX: [7] Payroll Signet Bank, 1991 (Box-folder 65:8)
      - Transition CSXS: [8] Cash Calculations, 1991 (Box-folder 65:9)
      - Transition CSX: [9] Payroll, 1991 (Box-folder 65:10)
      - Transition CSX: [10] Approach, 1991 (Box-folder 65:11)
      - Transition CSX: [11] To Do, 1991(?) (Box-folder 65:12)
      - Transition CSX: [12] Receipts, 1991 (Box-folder 65:13)
      - Transition CSX: [13] Organization, 1991 (Box-folder 65:14)
      - Transition CSX: [14] fixed assets, 1991 (Box-folder 65:15)
      - Transition CSX: [15] Transaction Cutoff, Memos/Record, 1991 (Box-folder 65:16)
      - Transition CSX: [16] Bank wire problem, 1991 (Box-folder 65:17)
      - Transition CSX: [17] Outstanding Issues, 1991 (Box-folder 65:18)
      - Transition CSX: [18] Property Taxes, Prorate, 1991 (Box-folder 65:19)
      - Transition CSX: [19] Land and easements conveyed, 29 Jul 1991 (Box-folder 65:20)
      - Transition CSX:[20]Cost of Sale, 1991 (Box-folder 65:21)
      - Transition CSX: [21] Pro Forma Balance sheets - RRB, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 65:22)
      - Transition CSX: [23] Missing and incomplete schedules and exhibits, 1991 (Box-folder 65:23)
      - Transition CSX: [24] Investments and partnerships, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 65:24)
      - Transition CSX: [25] Potomac Yard Retirements, 5 Dec 1991 (Box-folder 66:1)
      - Transition CSX: [73] APA - Asset Purchase Agreement, working copies, 1991 (Box-folder 66:2-3)
      - Transition CSX: [74] Asset Purchase Agreement, 28 Aug 1991 (Box-folder 66:4-6)
    - III.A.4. Statements, 1990-1991
      - Statements of Consolidated Earnings for 1986-1991 (Box-folder 66:7)
      - Statements of Earnings, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 66:8)
      - Statements of Income and Cash flows, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 66:9)
      - Statements to Board, 1991 (Box-folder 66:10-11)
        Includes: financial statements, balance sheet, worksheet, income statement, sources for income statement.
      - Statements to Board, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 66:12)
        Includes: operation expenses and income, statements, and balance sheets.
  - III.B. Accounting and Bookkeeping, 1834-1995
    Organized into the following categories: 1. Accounts; 2. Annual Reports; 3. Audits; 4. Balances; 5. Check Registers; 6. Daybooks; 7. Income and Expenses; 8. Journals; 9. Ledgers; 10. Property; 11. Vouchers
    - III.B.1. Accounts, n.d., ca. 1834-1978
      - Construction Cost for Bridges, n.d. (Box-folder 66a:1)
      - Equipment, Expenses, Real Estate, 1834-1845 (Box-folder 66a:2)
      - Expenses Charged to Income and Operating Expenses, 1834-1862 (Box-folder 66a:3)
      - New Construction Charges to Operation Expenses, 1901-1902 (Box-folder 66a:4)
      - Rental and Operating Expenses: Acca Yard, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 66a:5-6)
      - Roadway Completion Reports (Abbreviations V.S. and W.S. 2, e.g. refer to the different valuation sections)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenses), [V.S.2], 1916-1918, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), [V.S.2], 1919-1921, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), [V.S.2], 1922-1924, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), [V.S.2], 1925-1927, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), [V.S.1], 1928-1932, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), [V.S.1], 1933-1940, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), [W.S.-V.S.4], 1916-1919, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), [V.S.4-W.S.2], 1920-1927, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), 1930-1978, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenditures), 1974-1978, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenses), 1941-1945, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenses), 1946-1949, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenses), 1950-1953, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenses), 1954-1957, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)
        - Roadway Completion Report (General Account I, Road, and III, General Expenses), 1958-1963, 1 vol. (Volume on shelf)